Christopher Goodwin

User Experience Developer

802-540-5036

hello@christophergoodwin.me

christophergoodwin.me

linkedin.com/in/goodwinc

About

I believe in building a web that works for everyone, everywhere. Using primarily HTML & CSS, I write performant and maintainable code that's fast, responsive, and accessible.

I've had the privilege of building world class web experiences with companies such as Apple, Netflix, CIEE, and Sparta Science.

Experience

Senior User Experience Developer at DockYard

2016 - Present

- Leading UX development on internal and public-facing web apps with companies including Apple, Netflix, and Sparta Science
- · Working collaboratively with team members to translate designs into semantic, reliable code
- · Writing and auditing code to ensure accessibility, performance, and graceful degradation
- Refining coding standards while growing company understanding of best practices
- · Mentoring and teaching colleagues seeking improvement in front-end skills
- · Co-working remotely with an entirely distributed team

Front End Web Developer at Council on International Education Exchange

2014 - 2016

- Worked with a team to design and develop responsive and accessible websites
- · Estimated timelines and scoped work to meet project deadlines
- · Maintained and updated over 20 marketing websites

Freelance Web Developer

2011 - 2014

- · Designed, developed, and maintained corporate and personal websites
- · Spent time with clients to learn about their needs and products
- Enabled clients to create and grow their brands
- · Trained clients to update and maintain their sites for long term use

Skills

Education

- HTML and CSS proficiency with focus on semantic, maintainable code
- Strong understanding of accessibility best practices
- Design experience and familiarity with modern design software
- · Background in Javascript development
- Working knowledge of Git and version control
- Experience working remotely
- · Photography and video production background

BS in Web and Interactive Media

Pennsylvania College of Technology
 The Art Institute of New England
 2010 - 2011

Certificate of Completion

Center for Technology, Essex
 2008 - 2010